Ignacio Soto . Jarvis Consulting

I am a Business Systems Analyst with more than 2 years of experience working closely with business and technical stake-holders, understanding business needs, identifying requirements, and designing and implementing technology solutions. I have successfully increased process efficiency and improved decision-making using Macros, SQL, Tableau and Power BI. I have experience gathering, interpreting data to solve complex problems, and communicating my findings. As for my educational background, I hold a bachelor's degree in Systems Engineering and a postgraduate certificate in Business Analytics and Insights. On my free time, I play soccer, video games, and I like to go to the stadiums to see Toronto FC, Blue Jays, Maple Leafs, and Raptors.

Skills

Proficient: RDBMS/SQL, Power BI, Tableau, Microsoft Excel, Documentation

Competent: Python, Git, Google Cloud Platform, Agile, Scrum

Familiar: Java, Docker, Regex, Linux, R

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/Jarvis-Consulting-Group/jarvis_data_eng-ignaciosoto04

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: The Jarvis team has a Linux cluster of 10 servers running CentOS 7 which are connected through a switch and communicate through IPv4 addresses. The objective of this project is to design and implement a solution that allows recording the hardware specifications of each node and monitoring node resource usage in real-time and stored in a (RDBMS). This solution will help the resource planning team as they will be able to use the data to generate reports. The implementation of the program required to book an elicitation meeting with the stakeholder to create a BRD.

Highlighted Projects

Credit Score Classification [GitHub]: Developed a machine learning model that can classify customers' credit scores in a matter of seconds. The machine learning supervised methods used were Logistic Regression, Decision Tree, Random Forest, Neural Networks, Support Vector Machine, Naïve Bayes, XGBoost. This could generate great profits by giving loans and credits to clients who have a good credit score and knowing that their classification has been analyzed correctly.

Professional Experiences

Business Systems Analyst, Jarvis (2020-present): DAnalyzed business processes and information systems identifying areas of improvement to recommend solutions. Developed Business and Sofware Requirements Documents with Agile/Scrum methodology.

Data and Reporting Analyst, ClaimSecure (2022-2023): Investigated and scoped requirements for scheduled and ad hoc analytical and reporting needs for ClaimSecure internal and external clients. Developed, audited, documented, and delivered analysis and reports meeting established deadlines with a goal of 100% accuracy. Participated and supported Team Lead in new strategies and opportunities to increase and optimize customer experiences, revenue generation, ad targeting and other business outcomes.

Logistics Data Analyst Summer Intern, DAP Canada (2022): Supported core supply chain functions: logistics planning, inventory management, order processing and customer service coordination. Developed daily order delivered reports and dashboards to managers and CEO through Excel and Tableau. Scheduled appointments with carriers and customers warehouses, coordinating delivery according to required dates in the Warehouse Management System.

Operations Data Analyst, Fajitex (2019-2021): Designed production reports and dashboards for managers and stakeholders that effectively communicates trends, patterns, and predictions using Power BI. Worked with internal teams to identify process improvement opportunities and propose system modifications.

Education

Centennial College (2021-2022), Post Graduate Certificate, Business Analytics and Insights - Graduated with Honors - GPA: 3.9

University of Lima (2014-2018), Bachelor's Degree, Systems Engineering - Graduated with Honors

Miscellaneous

- Data Science course BranStation (2023)
- Advanced SQL Kaggle (2022)
- Excel Associate Microsoft (2021)
- Captain of a soccer team in a competitive league.
- Fan of cooperative video games like CS GO, Fortnite and Fifa Pro Clubs where a team strategy is needed to win.
- Volunteer for Community Infrastructure Projects: information gathering, planning and construction of houses in low-income areas in Lima, Peru.